play high
玩得高
move
移动
good
好的
You two are indeed here
你们两个确实在这里
Jiaping
Jiaping
You've been eyeing Zuo Shuangtao for a long time, right?
你盯上左双涛很久了吧？
If someone hadn't told me
如果没有人告诉我
I do not know yet
我还不知道
Mr. Sir
先生先生
stop fighting
别打了
go away
离开
open
打开
stop fighting
别打了
Get out of the way
走开
Section Chief Chen Section Chief Chen
陈科长 陈科长
go away
离开
Get rid of the gas, get rid of the gas
排除毒气，排除毒气
Step aside
靠边站
Where else have you been?
还有什么地方你去过？
Section Chief Chen
陈科长
where have they been
他们去哪儿了
Is there any need to say that?
有必要这么说吗？
Hotel
酒店
two knives
两把刀
Don't talk nonsense
别乱说
We are both innocent
我们都是无辜的
If you are innocent
如果你是无辜的
Then Captain Zhao and
然后是赵队长和
Are you okay bro?
兄弟你还好吗？
So careless
如此粗心
What's this
这是什么
do not move
不要动
you give me
你给我
Give me
给我吗
do not move
不要动
explain
解释
What is written here
这里写的是什么
Say what is this?
说说这是什么？
elder brother
哥哥
Is it a secret message?
这是秘密消息吗？
have a look
看一看
you give me
你给我
do not move
不要动
double peach
双桃
my sweetheart
我的爱人
elder brother
哥哥
I'll come, I'll come
我来我来
How are you
你好吗
Farewell for many days
告别多日
Miss you endlessly
无尽地想念你
I asked several times before asking
问之前问了好几次
It turns out you went to Shanghai
原来你去了上海
You left Wuhan
你离开了武汉
Didn't even say a word to me
甚至没有对我说一句话
I think you have really changed your mind
我认为你真的改变了主意
In fact, over the past half year or so
事实上，过去半年多的时间
I have noticed
我注意到了
You are really becoming less and less interested in me
你真的对我越来越不感兴趣了
But I still didn't think of it
但我还是没有想到
You will be so heartless
你会如此无情
in recent days
最近几天
I'm tossing and turning
我辗转反侧
It’s hard to let go
很难放手
I always think of the time we spent together
我总是想起我们一起度过的时光
us at that time
那时的我们
Qingqing Zipei
Qingqing Zipei
I'm thinking
我在想
Not seen for a day
一天不见了
Like March
喜欢三月
Mountains are high and rivers are long
山高水长
I miss you so much
我真的很想你
hold an umbrella
撑伞
make a pot of tea
泡一壶茶
Counting the time with you
数着和你在一起的时间
I really want to be like that
我真的很想成为那样
Tenchojiku
天长寺
Did you write it?
你写的吗？
I didn't write this
我没写这个
Not written by you
不是你写的
Gao Fang said he didn’t write it
高放说他没写？？？
Then who wrote this?
那么这是谁写的呢？
Who wrote it
谁写的
Remember?
记住？
repeat
重复
After meeting Gao Fang at Qinka Cafe
在琴卡咖啡馆遇见高放后
Confirm the secret message in hand first
先确认手上的密文
Then wait for an opportunity to poison the coffee
然后伺机给咖啡下毒
finally, I understand
终于，我明白了
Guoguo assassinates Yamashita
Guoguo assassinates Yamashita
It's to get back a secret letter
是为了取回一封密信
But then I don’t know why the secret message was lost again
但后来不知道为什么密文又丢失了
She once suspected that the secret message had been taken away by me.
她一度怀疑密信被我拿走了。
It turns out that the secret letter is in Gao Fang's hands
原来密信在高放手里
And used this to force Guoguo to date him
还以此逼果果和他约会
Now the military commander wants to take action against Gao
现在军统要对高采取行动
But Guoguo definitely doesn’t know
但果果肯定不知道？？？
Zhang Shuyun saw her meeting with Gao Fang
张淑云看到她和高放见面
And Zhang Shuyun will definitely inform Zhao An of this matter.
而这件事情张淑云一定会通知赵安的。
So the actions of military commanders
所以军事指挥官的行动
It's possible that they are all under Zhao An's surveillance
很可能他们都在赵安的监视之下
Na Guoguo’s identity
Na Guoguo???s identity
It's completely exposed
已经完全暴露了
You two are indeed here
你们两个确实在这里
Jiaping
Jiaping
You've been eyeing Zuo Shuangtao for a long time, right?
你盯上左双涛很久了吧？
If someone hadn't told me
如果没有人告诉我
I do not know yet
我还不知道
You two are too brave.
你们两个也太勇敢了吧
Jiaping
Jiaping
he and I
他和我
We met in Wuhan
我们相识在武汉
what relationship
什么关系
What's their relationship?
他们是什么关系？
Isn't this obvious?
这不是很明显吗？
really
真的
Been together for a while
在一起有一段时间了
I didn’t expect it, Zuo Shuangtao
没想到啊左双涛
Two boats
两艘船
Who knows if there are only two boats?
谁知道是否只有两艘船？
Get out of here
离开这里
Jiaping
Jiaping
We only have a short period of time
我们只有很短的时间
It's very short
很短
You will be with him forever
你会永远和他在一起
We're going to spend a lifetime together
我们要一起度过一生
you tell me a short time
你告诉我一会儿
He is the kind of person who is sour.
他是那种酸酸的人。
It's just talk
这只是说说而已
I didn't take it seriously at all
我根本没认真对待
you didn't take it seriously
你没有认真对待它
Why did you leave this letter?
你为什么留下这封信？
I just received it
我刚收到
Originally I wanted to get rid of it
原本我想摆脱它
But then I couldn't find it
但后来我找不到了
I thought it was lost
我以为丢了
You thought you lost it
你以为你失去了它
Did you receive this letter?
你收到这封信了吗？
You must have lost your soul with excitement.
你一定兴奋得失去了灵魂。
So what do you want from me?
你想要我做什么？
During that time, war was raging
那段时间，战事如火如荼
We are separated again
我们又分开了
a letter i wrote to you
我写给你的一封信
two months
两个月
I didn't receive a reply for two months
我两个月没有收到回复
I don't even dare to think about it
我连想都不敢想
Can we still be together?
我们还能在一起吗？
Can you survive tomorrow?
明天你能活下去吗？
I don't even know
我什至不知道
We are all degraded people
我们都是堕落的人
That is
那是
Have a better time
过得更好
What's wrong
怎么了
You are still reasonable
你还是讲道理的
How dare you hit me
你怎么敢打我
roll
卷
I never want to see you again
我再也不想见到你
What are you looking at?
你在看什么？
Never seen it
没见过
letter
信
How could it be on you
怎么会落在你身上
I
我
Did you steal it from Zuo Shuangtao?
是你从左双涛那里偷来的吗？
say
说
to be honest
说实话
yes
是的
I got it from her
我从她那里得到的
I always
我总是
Secretly in love with Miss Zuo
暗恋左小姐
So that day she came to work at the commercial bank
于是那天她来到商业银行上班
When I helped her move things
当我帮她搬东西时
took it from her pocket
从她的口袋里拿出来
So you use this letter
所以你用这封信
Threaten my wife
威胁我的妻子
Date with you
与你约会
Is it right
这样对吗
right
正确的
good
好的
I'll ask you one last time
我最后一次再问你一次
Have you done anything else with my wife?
你还对我妻子做过什么吗？
I don't
我不
I I'm really just with her
我真的只是和她在一起
Come out and talk
出来说话
I really didn't do anything else
我真的没有做任何其他事
Okay, Jiaping
好的，家平
calm down
冷静下来
Walk
走
Captain Zhao
Captain Zhao
Why are you here?
你为什么在这？
passing by
经过
Want to come in and have a cup of coffee
想进来喝杯咖啡
Something happened to you
你出了什么事
OK
好的
You can go
你可以走了
Drink coffee
喝咖啡
Can you drink high and put a letter in your pocket?
你能喝高酒并在口袋里放一封信吗？
two knives
两把刀
Is this interesting
这有趣吗
Gao Fang and Zuo Shuangtao just have a cup of coffee
高放和左双涛刚刚喝了杯咖啡
What does it have to do with you
跟你有什么关系
You must help Section Chief Chen find out the truth
你一定要帮陈科长查明真相
What other love letters should I find?
我还应该找到哪些其他情书？
token of love
爱情的信物
Let me turn it over
让我把它翻过来
Have you turned it over?
你翻过来了吗？
You made Section Chief Chen
你成就了陈科长
The misunderstanding between Zuo Shuangtao and the others deepened
左双涛等人误会加深
Don't you want to demolish your home?
你不想拆你的家吗？
No
不
How to explain
如何解释
How can I explain
我该如何解释
Explain it
解释一下
roll
卷
Acting is too tiring
演戏太累了
Fortunately, the tacit understanding is good
还好默契不错
Is this what you want?
这是你想要的吗？
Don't you ask me what this is?
你不问我这是什么吗？
If you want to tell me
如果你想告诉我
It's not like he was coerced by Gao Fang, right?
不会是被高放胁迫吧？
At least there will be speculation.
至少会有猜测。
I don't want to guess
我不想猜测
I am
我是
dawdle
混日子
Eat together
一起吃
Where are these secrets of yours?
你的这些秘密在哪里？
I don't want to know either
我也不想知道
Not interested either
也不感兴趣
Moreover
而且
know your secret
知道你的秘密
Doesn't do me any good either
对我也没有任何好处
Then how do you know
那你怎么知道
Gao Fang used this to coerce me
高放拿这个来胁迫我
When you and Gao Zang met at Mega Park,
当你和高藏在Mega Park相遇时，
Zhang Shuyun saw it
张淑云看到了
Then it reached Lu Fangfang’s ears
然后就传到了陆芳芳的耳朵里
What a careless
多么不小心
did not expect
没想到
In the end, it was a woman’s long tongue that helped me
最后，是女人的长舌头帮了我
no matter what
无论
Thank you
谢谢
Why are you thanking me?
你为什么要感谢我？
I still have to say sorry to you.
我还是要对你说一声对不起。
I deducted one for you
我给你扣了一笔
Unfounded bad reputation
毫无根据的坏名声
And slapped you
还打了你一巴掌
It's no big deal, right?
没什么大不了的，对吧？
I have nothing
我什么都没有
It's for you
这是给你的
Cuckolded
戴绿帽子
Plus two knives
加上两把刀
Adding fuel to the fire
火上浇油
Enough to be laughed at for a while
足够被人笑一阵子了
yes
是的
And from now on
并且从现在开始
Luo Guanqun and I have more common topics.
我和罗冠群有更多共同话题。
You come to Shanghai
你来上海
Just for this
只为这个
So now you've got it
所以现在你已经明白了
I will go
我要走了
do you think
你认为
I used you
我利用了你
No
不
look
看
the two of us
我们俩
Help each other solve their own troubles
互相帮助解决各自的烦恼
Isn't this good?
这不是很好吗？
Just now I was thinking here
刚才我在想这里
I just understand
我才明白
It turns out you took every detail into consideration
原来你考虑到了每一个细节
If it hadn't been for that slap in the face
如果不是那一巴掌
There is no way I can leave so simply.
我不可能就这么简单的离开。
If you were an agent
如果你是代理人
It must be the top
一定是顶级的
Stop it
停下来
What kind of agent am I?
我是个什么样的代理人？
At best, I'm just a beaten thief.
充其量，我只是一个被打败的小偷。
Right
正确的
I have a longer memory
我的记忆力更长
Why are you hanging out with traitors?
为什么要和叛徒混在一起？
Think about it
想一想
On the beach in Shanghai
在上海的海滩上
right
正确的
Let's eat together
我们一起吃饭吧
But I think
但我觉得
You also have something like this
你也有这样的事情
what
什么
Secret
秘密
have a secret from me
对我有秘密
But I'm also worried about you
但我也担心你
We just got married not long ago
我们刚结婚不久
I just left
我刚刚离开
Will they doubt you again?
他们会再次怀疑你吗？
Won't
惯于
Think about it
想一想
You gave me a big green hat
你给了我一顶大绿帽子
I slapped you
我打了你一巴掌
It's like this
就像这样
We parted ways
我们分道扬镳
Isn't that normal?
这不是很正常吗？
He won't doubt it
他不会怀疑
This is the result you want
这就是你想要的结果
Yeah
是的
Now
现在
For both of us
为了我们俩
this
这
These are the best results, right?
这是最好的结果，对吧？
right
正确的
Just a play
只是一场戏
only
仅有的
Our acting skills are so good
我们的演技真好
Acting well
演技不错
I almost believed it
我几乎相信了
And you
你呢
Do you feel this way?
你有这样的感觉吗？
I feel like I almost believed it
我感觉我几乎相信了
If this were a movie
如果这是一部电影
I hope it can go on forever
我希望它可以永远持续下去
goodbye
再见
Why didn't you kill Gao Fang?
为什么不杀掉高放？
many things
很多东西
It can't be solved by killing people
不是杀人就能解决的
how did you do that
你是怎么做到的
I have my way
我有我的办法
He returned the secret message to me
他把秘密信息回复给我
Back to you
回到你身边
Why didn't I see it?
为什么我没看到？
Maybe you didn't care
或许你并没有在意
How did you convince him?
你是怎么说服他的？
Women have women's ways
女人有女人的方式
Especially when facing a
尤其是当面对一个
When you like your own person
当你喜欢自己的人时
But I clearly saw it
但我清楚地看到了
You poisoned the coffee?
你在咖啡里下了毒？
I replaced the poison with water
我用水代替了毒药
If Gao Fang is not dead
如果高放没死
You will take action
你将采取行动
But in that case
但在那种情况下
There's no way I can tell you I got it
我没办法告诉你我明白了
You are good at making opinions again
你又善于发表意见
Zhao An has been monitoring me and Gao Fang
赵安一直在监视我和高放
If I hadn't made the decision
如果我没有做出这个决定
We can still stand here and talk
我们仍然可以站在这里说话
I hope you have merit
希望你有功德
I don't care about you
我不关心你
Get on board first
先上船
Let’s talk about it after leaving Shanghai
离开上海再说吧
where to
去哪儿
To Jiaxing
To Jiaxing
There is a traffic line over there
那边有一条交通线
Then find a way to get to Chongqing
然后想办法去重庆
Let's go
我们走吧
You said that thing
你说那件事
I'll help you keep an eye on it
我会帮你关注的
Contact you if found
如果找到请联系您
good
好的
okay
然后慢慢走，别错过两个boss。
Don't give it away
不要放弃它
Good words
良言
Looks like you're in a good mood today
看来你今天心情不错
old road
老路
This is a secret message from the military commander
这是来自军事指挥官的秘密消息
Gao Fang has translated part of it
高芳翻译了部分内容
The remaining part
剩下的部分
Please organize and arrange experts to continue deciphering
请组织安排专家继续解密
Since this secret letter
自从这封密信
So important for military unification
对于军事统一如此重要
There must be some confidential information here
这里一定有一些机密信息
There are still old roads
依然有老路
Zuo Shuangtao
Zuo Shuangtao
Already evacuated
已经撤离
Crisis resolved
危机解决
Can I apply?
我可以申请吗？
Keep lurking
继续潜伏
But still can't let down our guard
但仍不能放松警惕
How is the secret peace talks going?
秘密和谈进展如何？
Two Japanese representatives
两名日本代表
No clues yet
还没有任何线索
But there is new progress
但又有新进展了
I'm still tracing
我还在追寻
According to some intelligence analysis
根据一些情报分析
Chiang Kai-shek is likely to be involved in this peace negotiation
蒋介石很可能参与这次和平谈判
Abandon the policy of resisting Japan and tolerating communism
放弃抗日容共政策
Even recognized the so-called Manchukuo
甚至承认所谓的满洲国
This is not a peace talk
这不是和平谈判
This is clearly betraying the country.
这明显是背叛国家。
But if there is no hard evidence
但如果没有确凿的证据
Chongqing will never admit it
重庆绝对不会承认
so your task
所以你的任务
extremely important
极其重要
clear
清除
Prepare today
今天准备
What are you taking with you?
你带了什么？
You can take anything
你可以拿走任何东西
this is not OK
这不行
This is a flower-and-bird pattern brush carved from bamboo during the Wanli period of the Ming Dynasty.
这是明代万历年间用竹子雕刻的花鸟纹毛笔。
It’s my treasure
这是我的宝藏
you
你
Absolutely not
绝对不
Tell me about you
介绍一下你自己吧
Married only a few days
结婚才几天
How come it's like this?
怎么会这样呢？
This cuckold is on my head
这个戴绿帽子在我头上
If it were you, you could bear it
如果是你，你可以忍受
Take the overall situation into consideration
顾全大局
How can I take care of the overall situation?
怎样才能顾全大局呢？
How can I take care of the overall situation, Lao Luo?
老罗我怎么顾全大局？
Just one day
就一天
The news spread throughout all the trading houses.
这个消息传遍了各大商行。
when i came in
当我进来的时候
The way everyone looks at me is wrong
每个人看我的方式都是错误的
It's like my face is covered
就像我的脸被遮住了一样
Everything has turned green for me
对我来说一切都变绿了
My face is green now, right?
我现在脸都绿了是吗？
OK OK OK
好好好
Not green
不绿色
No one is green
没有人是绿色的
Men should be a little open-minded
男人应该心胸开阔一点
Otherwise, how could it be such a big deal?
不然怎么会出这么大的事？
I didn't mean it to be a big deal
我并不想有什么大不了的
As long as you can achieve great things
只要你能成就伟大的事情
I'll hang out with you
我会和你一起出去玩
Just have something to eat.
只要吃点东西就可以了。
you say you
你说你
Where is Miss Zuo?
左小姐在哪儿？
Ran
然
Then why don't you go look for it?
那你为什么不去找找呢？
How can I find it?
我怎样才能找到它？
I slapped her
我打了她一巴掌
I can get her temper back
我能让她恢复脾气
What a pity about my vegetable oil business
我的植物油生意真可惜
Not what do you mean?
不是你说的是什么意思？
Your business is business
你的生意就是生意
Your brother’s face is not a face
你哥哥的脸不是脸
OK OK OK
好好好
You are totally unreliable
你完全不可靠
What do you mean I'm unreliable?
你说我不可靠是什么意思？
When I was the most uncomfortable and wronged
在我最难受、最委屈的时候
If you don't comfort me, forget it
如果你不安慰我，那就算了吧
Are you adding insult to injury?
你这是雪上加霜吗？
are you my brother
你是我兄弟吗
I treat you as a brother
我把你当兄弟
Do you consider me a brother?
你把我当兄弟吗？
You told me last time you liked this stuff
上次你告诉我你喜欢这个东西
I tried my best to find it for you
我尽力为你找到它
What do I do if I find you?
如果找到你我该怎么办？
I'm done with pouting.
我已经撅嘴了。
By distinction
按区别
This is baby
这是宝贝
Get off
下车
By distinction
按区别
This is baby, this is baby
这是宝贝，这是宝贝
You let go, let go
你放手，放手
I was joking just now
我刚才是开玩笑的
I apologize
我道歉
loosen loosen loosen loosen
松开 松开 松开 松开
What I just said were all angry words
我刚才说的都是愤怒的话
You are unreliable
你不可靠
Who can be trusted?
谁可以信任？
Where did you get this?
你从哪里得到这个？
You don’t care where I got it from
你不在乎我从哪里得到它
I tell you
我告诉你
If you're to blame for this, blame Zhao An
如果这件事要怪你，就怪赵安吧
He is everywhere
他无处不在
What’s the latest news about Feng Qi?
冯琪的最新消息是什么？
This guy has been disappearing all day long
这家伙整天不见踪影
There must be some secret mission
一定有什么秘密任务
do you have any news
你有什么消息吗
When I went to the military police headquarters for a meeting
当我去宪兵司令部开会时
I heard Kimura and Zhao An muttering something?
我听到木村和赵安嘀咕着什么？
I only heard one person's name
我只听过一个人的名字
Jiang Zhaoguo
Jiang Zhaoguo
right
正确的
I have no idea
我不知道
Does he have anything to do with Feng Qi's recent mission?
他和风起最近的任务有什么关系吗？
have no idea
不知道
Jiang Zhaoguo
Jiang Zhaoguo
Sadness can be contagious to others
悲伤会传染给别人
Happiness can also infect others
快乐也能感染别人
so
所以
hope i'm with you
希望我和你在一起
It's a little more sad
又多了一点悲伤
Still happier
还是比较开心
play high
玩得高
I know you have a lot of worries
我知道你有很多烦恼
But as long as we face the sunshine together
但只要我们一起面对阳光
It will all pass
一切都会过去的
Just smile
只是笑一下
Really ugly
真丑
come and learn from me
来跟我学吧
knew
知道
Jiaping
Jiaping
This is Xiao Jin, the person in charge here
这是肖金，这里的负责人
This newspaper is full of these news
这份报纸充满了这些新闻
If you have anything, just ask him
如果你有什么事就问他
Entertainment gossip
娱乐八卦
Celebrity Scandal
名人丑闻
Shocking revelations
令人震惊的爆料
sexy nude photos
性感裸体照片
We have whatever we want here
我们这里有我们想要的一切
What do you want to know?
你想知道什么？
Does Hanlu know?
韩璐知道吗？
Do our job
做好我们的工作
How could you not recognize Hanlu?
你怎么会不认识韩璐呢？
There is another name
还有另一个名字
My name is Jiang Zhaoguo
My name is Jiang Zhaoguo
Do you have an impression?
你有印象吗？
Jiang Zhaoguo
Jiang Zhaoguo
This name is a bit unfamiliar
这个名字有点陌生
You put Jiang Zhaoguo and Han Lu
You put Jiang Zhaoguo and Han Lu
These two names are associated with each other
这两个名字是相互关联的
Jiang Zhaoguo
Jiang Zhaoguo
cold dew
冷露
wait
等待
I said why is it a bit strange?
我说怎么有点奇怪呢？
This was news two years ago
这是两年前的新闻
This mysterious boyfriend
这个神秘的男友
His name is Jiang Zhaoguo
His name is Jiang Zhaoguo
At that time, he was an official of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the Nationalist Government
时任国民政府外交部官员
thank you
谢谢
go ahead
前进
i know now
我现在知道了
Why are they looking for Hanlu?
他们为什么要找韩璐？
What's the matter with you?
你怎么了？
No eyes
没有眼睛
sorry
对不起
sorry Sorry
实在抱歉
Sugar-coated haws
冰糖葫芦
Miss
错过
I will contact you when there is news about the house.
当有关于房子的消息时我会联系你。
Walk slowly
慢慢走
good
好的
You two, stop here
你们两个，停在这里
That's right, it's you two
没错，就是你们两个
I said you two are
我说你们两个是
Are they husband and wife or lovers?
他们是夫妻还是恋人？
It’s not that you have big eyes
不是因为你眼睛大
for breathing
用于呼吸
We are both men
我们都是男人
Since they are all men
因为他们都是男人
Two people make love every day
两个人每天都做爱
What are you doing hanging around in the French Concession?
你在法租界闲逛做什么？
Such a wide road
这么宽阔的路
Are you taking too much care?
你是不是太在意了？
Don't talk nonsense to me here
别在这里跟我废话
Don't think I don't know
别以为我不知道
Have you two always
你们两个总是
Follow that pretty lady who just came in?
跟着刚刚进来的那位漂亮女士吗？
There are so many people on the road
路上有这么多人
Why are you following her just because you said it was us?
为什么你只因为说是我们就跟踪她？
I tell you
我告诉你
I'm the patrolman of the French Concession
我是法租界的巡警
don't let me see it again
别让我再看到它
You are sneaking around in the French Concession
你在法租界偷偷摸摸
What should you do?
你该怎么办？
Take a look at this set
看看这套
No. 22, Petain Road, French Concession
法租界贝当路22号
This area is a high-end residential area
该区域为高档住宅区
All the upper class people live here
上流社会的人都住在这里
Not only is the environment beautiful
不仅环境优美
And ah
还有啊
There is also a patrol house patrolling 24 hours a day.
还有巡逻所，24小时巡逻。
Of course, the price will be slightly higher
当然价格会稍微高一些
Price is not an issue
价格不是问题
but
但
I don't want anyone to know
我不想让任何人知道
I rented a house with you
我和你合租了房子
Don't worry about this
不用担心这个
We will never leak it
我们绝不会泄露
any information about customers
有关客户的任何信息
coming
未来
Miss Hanlu
韩璐小姐
Jiaping
Jiaping
why are you here
你为什么在这
Can I talk to you in the car?
我可以在车上和你说话吗？
What to talk about
聊什么
about a friend of yours
关于你的一个朋友
Miss Hanlu
韩璐小姐
You rented the house for that friend, right?
你把房子租给那个朋友了，对吗？
how
如何
you follow me
你跟着我
No
不
Don't get me wrong
别误会我的意思
We are not stalking you
我们不是在跟踪你
Instead, you followed the person who followed you.
相反，您关注了关注您的人。
I didn't find anyone following me
我没有发现有人关注我
If Miss Hanlu finds out
如果韩露小姐知道的话
Those colleagues of mine
我的那些同事
He must have been shot a long time ago
他一定是很久以前就被枪杀了
so now
所以现在
You can talk to me
你可以跟我说话
What’s the story about your friend?
你的朋友有什么故事吗？
If Miss Hanlu
如果韩露小姐
What you still don’t want to tell me
你还不想告诉我什么
I can reveal some information to you first
我可以先向你透露一些信息
The Chongqing government is working with the Japanese Prime Minister
重庆市政府正与日本首相合作
Planning secret peace talks
策划秘密和谈
However, the Japanese military tried their best to obstruct
然而日军却极力阻挠
and bring the negotiators from both sides
并带来双方谈判代表
They were all listed as targets for assassination.
他们都被列为暗杀目标。
And the Chongqing government
还有重庆市政府
Deputy Director-General of the Asian Department of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs
外交部亚洲司副司长
Jiang Zhaoguo
Jiang Zhaoguo
He is the representative of China this time
这次他是中国代表
I'm just an actor
我只是一个演员
Not interested in political matters
对政治问题不感兴趣
This person you are talking about
你正在谈论的这个人
I don't know him either
我也不认识他
good
好的
But
但
I still have to remind Miss Hanlu
还是要提醒韩露小姐
The people following you are Zhao An's men
跟着你的人是赵安的手下
So the house you rent is no longer safe
所以你租的房子不再安全
Can I get off the car?
我可以下车吗？
certainly
当然
Hello
你好
it's me
这就是我
Have you rented the house?
你租到房子了吗？
I'm being followed
我被跟踪了
there are two people
有两个人
Followed me to the rental company
跟着我到了租赁公司
What
什么
you
你
Do you see who they are?
你看到他们是谁了吗？
I happened to meet a friend
我碰巧遇见了一个朋友
know those two people
认识那两个人
They are the Military Police Headquarters
他们是宪兵司令部
A subordinate of a secret intelligence station
秘密情报站的下属
You're not in danger, are you?
你没有危险吧？
No
不
But that house
但那个房子
You don't have to worry about the house.
你不用担心房子的问题。
I will figure it out myself
我自己会解决的
sorry
对不起
I can't help you
我帮不了你
No
不
It was my fault
是我的错
i shouldn't
我不应该
Implicate you in my work
让你参与我的工作
I am worried about you
我很替你担心
those people
那些人
Will I also find you?
我也会去找你吗？
Do not worry
不用担心
they won't find me
他们不会找到我
Where I live is very secluded.
我住的地方非常僻静。
Are you coming to Shanghai this time?
这次你来上海吗？
What exactly is the job?
这份工作到底是什么？
this
这
i can't tell you
我不能告诉你
Very dangerous, right?
非常危险，对吧？
I work
我的工作
Nothing is not dangerous
没有什么是不危险的
Then after you finish this work
然后当你完成这项工作后
Will you stay in Shanghai?
你会留在上海吗？
Going back to Chongqing?
回重庆？
I can't even tell now
我现在也说不清楚
It depends on the results of my work this time
就看我这次的工作成果了
So this time
所以这一次
There's no end to the meeting again
会议又没有结束
two days later
两天后
It's still this time
依然是这个时候
I will contact you again
我会再次联系你
keep in touch
保持联系
Is there anything else?
还有别的事吗？
I will give you an address then
那我给你一个地址
you come to me
你过来我这里
looking for you
寻找你
What are you looking for?
你要买什么？
I
我
I want to take you away
我想带你走
If it was two years ago
如果是两年前
You also said such things to me
你也对我说过这样的话
I will follow you without hesitation
我会毫不犹豫地追随你
Even if it means mountains of swords and seas of fire, I won’t hesitate
就算是刀山火海我也不会犹豫
But now
但现在
I know
我知道
I mean
我是说
if you are willing to
如果你愿意的话
Why
为什么
Why are you showing up again now?
你怎么现在又出现了？
I
我
It took me two full years
我花了整整两年的时间
Then I gradually forgot the pain
然后我就渐渐忘记了疼痛
I finally started my career again
我终于重新开始了我的职业生涯
my life
我的生活
But now you appear again
但现在你又出现了
Let these past events be vividly remembered
让这些往事历历在目
Why haven't you sailed yet?
怎么还没开船？
The river is blocked
河水被堵住了
After the lockdown is lifted
解除封锁后
let's go
我们走吧
You go back to sleep first
你先回去睡觉吧
stop
停止
I knew it
我就知道
that moment
那一刻
Did you read clearly what was on the note?
您是否清楚地阅读了纸条上的内容？
who is wild horse
谁是野马
my superior
我的上级
The telegram said
电报说
Secret peace talks have been leaked
秘密和谈已被泄露
The Gendarmerie Command has taken action
宪兵司令部已采取行动
what's going on
这是怎么回事
Recently, Chongqing has to negotiate with the Japanese government
近日，重庆要与日本政府交涉
A secret peace talk in Shanghai
上海秘密和谈
It's not the first time
这已经不是第一次了
What result can be reached?
能达到什么结果？
Wild horses let's try to protect the peace negotiators
野马让我们努力保护和平谈判者
Why are we leaving Shanghai?
我们为什么要离开上海？
This peace negotiation is not as simple as you think
这场和平谈判并不像你想象的那么简单
If you get stuck in it
如果你深陷其中
will bring very big consequences
会带来非常大的后果
If peace talks can bring the war to an early end
如果和谈可以让战争早日结束
What's wrong
怎么了
you are too naive
你太天真了
If I continue to lurk
如果我继续潜伏
You can definitely complete the task
你绝对可以完成任务
Your mission has been completed
你的使命已经完成
you are disobeying orders
你不服从命令
Order
命令
Order is business
订单就是生意
Some business can be done
有些生意可以做
Some businesses cannot be done
有些生意做不成
That's not what you told me
那不是你告诉我的
You say it is your duty to obey orders
你说服从命令是你的职责
I treat you as one of my own
我把你当作我自己的人
That’s why I’m telling you this
这就是为什么我告诉你这个
Refuse to perform tasks
拒绝执行任务
How do you explain it to your superiors?
你如何向上级解释？
I will tell them
我会吿诉他们的
around the river
河边
There is radio detection vehicle activity
有无线电探测车辆活动
We didn't use the radio
我们没有使用收音机
I didn't receive the order
我没有收到订单
besides
除了
Received the news
收到消息
Said Jiangmyeon will be unblocked tomorrow night
据说明晚江面将解封
before this
在这之前
Don't even think about leaving the cabin
甚至不想离开机舱
You'd better think about it carefully
你最好仔细考虑一下
Facing boss Dai’s reward
面对戴老板的奖励
How to behave well?
如何表现得好？
The illustrious military exploits you have made
你们所立下的赫赫战功
right there
在那里
Has anyone been in there?
有人去过那里吗？
Only the cold dew comes in and out
只有寒露进出
what is she busy with
她在忙什么
She bought a lot of things
她买了很多东西
what
什么
some tea red wine
一些茶红酒
and some food
和一些食物
wine
葡萄酒
Quite romantic
相当浪漫
which kind of food
哪种食物
Listen to Chen Shugan who is following her
听听跟踪她的陈树干的话
She also bought some ingredients for Chinese and Western food
她还买了一些中西餐的食材
I also went to a Japanese food store specifically
我还专门去了一家日本料理店
We're following the right place
我们正在追踪正确的地方
It seems that this negotiation will take a long time
看来这次谈判需要很长时间
Jiang Zhaoguo asked her to come here first to make some preparations.
蒋兆国让她先来这里做一些准备。
that person
那个人
It should be Jiang Zhaoguo
It should be Jiang Zhaoguo
Then should we take action?
那我们应该采取行动吗？
Don't alert the snake
不要惊动蛇
Wait for the Japanese representative to come
等待日本代表到来
Let's do it together
我们一起做吧
Han Lu, what is she doing?
韩露，她在做什么？
Xiao Wu eats
小吴吃饭
Wait for the boat to leave
等待船离开
Take off her chain
摘下她的链子
good
好的
Received another telegram from Ye Ye
又收到叶叶的电报
Still asking
还在问
leave them alone
别管他们
What's wrong
怎么了
Miss Hanlu
韩璐小姐
do you know
你知道吗
What a stupid thing you did
你做了多么愚蠢的事
what did i do
我做了什么
Follow you to the man at No. 22, Petain Road
跟着你到贝当路22号的那个人那里
It's not Jiang Zhaoguo at all, right?
根本就不是蒋兆国吧？
It's the actor you're looking for in the crew
这就是您在剧组中寻找的演员
In your last movie, "Spring Light"
在你的上一部电影《春光》中
He plays the bank manager
他扮演银行经理
You can't protect Jiang Zhaoguo at all by doing this.
你这样做根本保护不了蒋兆国。
You don't have to worry about my affairs
我的事你不用担心
It's not a question of whether you care or not
这不是你在意与否的问题
But if you say this
但如果你这么说
It will only put you in more danger
这只会让你陷入更大的危险
If Zhao An discovers
如果赵安发现
You are a puzzle
你是一个谜题
Interfering with their vision
干扰他们的视力
Then take a seat
然后坐下
You are related to Jiang Zhaoguo
You are related to Jiang Zhaoguo
Not only are there connections
不仅有联系
Are you still trying to cover up Jiang Zhaoguo?
你还想掩盖蒋兆国吗？
I told you before
我告诉过你
Jiang Zhaoguo is Zhao An’s assassination target
Jiang Zhaoguo is Zhao An???s assassination target
and now you
现在你
Became the one who could find Jiang Zhaoguo
成为了能找到蒋兆国的人
only clue
唯一的线索
So what will Zhao An do?
那么赵安会怎么做呢？
So what should I do now
那我现在该怎么办
Get out of here with me right now
现在跟我一起离开这里
But my new movie hasn’t been finished yet
但我的新电影还没拍完
Filmmaking is full of surprises
电影制作充满惊喜
There are some that have been filmed but not released yet.
有一些已经拍摄但尚未上映。
Say goodbye to your new movie
和你的新电影说再见
Miss Hanlu
韩璐小姐
This hotel is run by French people
这家酒店是法国人经营的
An invitation is required to enter
需要邀请函才能进入
you are safe here
你在这里很安全
Thank you
谢谢
You shouldn't thank me
你不应该感谢我
I should thank my friends
我应该感谢我的朋友们
Know-it-all about the French Concession
法租界的一切你都知道
Naruko
鸣子
It's an honor to serve you
很荣幸为您服务
Thanks
谢谢
Miss Hanlu
韩璐小姐
Now you can tell me
现在你可以告诉我
About Jiang Zhaoguo’s situation?
About Jiang Zhaoguo???s situation?
before him
在他之前
An official from the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the Nationalist Government
国民政府外交部官员
Previously in charge of concession affairs
此前负责特许经营事务
So I often come to Shanghai for business
所以我经常来上海出差
I met him two years ago
我两年前认识了他
But this time he suddenly appeared
但这一次他却突然出现
I don’t know what it is specifically.
我不知道具体是什么。
Just asked me to rent a house for him
刚刚让我给他租房子
Do you have his contact information?
你有他的联系方式吗？
No
不
He was the one who found me
他是找到我的人
Then you have an appointment
那么你有一个约会
Is it time to meet next time?
下次见面还有时间吗？
No
不
good
好的
Miss Hanlu
韩璐小姐
Have a good rest in the hotel
在酒店好好休息
Someone will bring you food every day
每天都会有人给你送食物
Don't open the curtains
不要打开窗帘
Don't leave the hotel even half a step
不要离开酒店半步
do you understand
你明白吗
good
好的
goodbye
再见
Is he in danger?
他有危险吗？
Very dangerous
非常危险
can you protect him
你能保护他吗
try your best
尽你所能
goodbye
再见
Where are you going?
你要去哪里？
Jiaxing
嘉兴
Several people
几个人
three
三
Show me the freight certificate.
请出示货运凭证。
They're all here
他们都在这里
pass
经过
Go get a new epidemic prevention certificate
去领新的防疫证件
I didn’t say I needed to prepare the epidemic prevention certificate before.
我之前没说要准备防疫证明啊。
There has been an epidemic of dysentery in Shanghai recently
近日，上海爆发了痢疾疫情。
An epidemic prevention certificate is required to enter and exit the pier
进出码头需持有防疫证明
If nothing can be done, go to the Shiliupu Wharf Clinic.
如果实在没有办法，就去十六铺码头诊所。
take inspection
接受检查
Then reissue
然后重新发出
Okay, I'll go right now
好的，我现在就去
All three of you have to go
你们三个都得走了
Master, this is me
主人，这就是我
Someone inside has a fever
里面有人发烧了
Another person takes care of her
另一个人照顾她
How about you
你呢
Can't I go by myself?
我自己去不行吗？
That won't work
那不行
Look at that
看那个
Sorry for causing trouble
抱歉造成麻烦
Okay, hurry up
好的，快点
Once the certificate is obtained, the ship will be dispatched.
一旦获得证书，船舶就会被派遣。
OK
好的
two days later
两天后
It's still this time
依然是这个时候
I will contact you again
我会再次联系你